Register of the O. J. (Oliver Julian) Todd papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- SPEECHES AND WRITINGS, 1899-1973
  - "Taming Flood Dragons Along China's Hwang Ho," National Geographic Magazine, correspondence, typescript draft, and printed copy, 1942 February
    Box/Folder 21: 17
  - Miscellaneous speech outline, 1944
    Box/Folder 21: 18
  - Miscellaneous speech outlines, 1945
    Box/Folder 21: 19
  - Article on UNRRA and the Chinese Communists, typescript, 1945
    Box/Folder 21: 20
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, drafts, and typescripts, 1946
    Box/Folder 21: 21
  - "Turning Back the Yellow River To Its Prewar Channel," Engineering News-Record, printed copy, 1946 October 31
    Box/Folder 21: 22
  - "Yellow River Project of 1946," The Far Eastern Engineer, correspondence, two typescript drafts, and printed copy, 1947 January-February
    Box/Folder 21: 23
  - Remarks, Huayuankou, typescript, 1947 May 4
    Box/Folder 21: 24
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, outlines, and typescript drafts, 1948
    Box/Folder 21: 25
  - "East Meets West in Controlling China's Yellow River," Civil Engineering, transcript draft and printed copy, 1948 October (Reel 36)
    Box/Folder 22: 1
  - "Post-war Repair of the Yellow River Dikes," The Military Engineer, typescript draft and printed copy, 1948 December
    Box/Folder 22: 2
  - Miscellaneous, 1949
    Box/Folder 22: 3
  - "The Yellow River Reharnessed," The Geographical Review, correspondence and two printed reprints, 1949
    Box/Folder 22: 4
  - Miscellaneous notes and background material, 1950
    Box/Folder 22: 5
  - "Mei-ling Soong," typescript article, 1950
    Box/Folder 22: 6
  - Miscellaneous notes, outlines, and correspondence, 1951
    Box/Folder 22: 7
  - Miscellaneous notes, outlines, and correspondence, 1952
    Box/Folder 22: 8
  - Miscellaneous notes and correspondence, 1953
    Box/Folder 22: 9
  - An American Engineer Looks at China, book outline, correspondence, and typescript draft, 1953
    Box/Folder 22: 10
  - Miscellaneous speech outline, 1954
    Box/Folder 22: 11
  - Miscellaneous notes, outlines, and correspondence, 1955
    Box/Folder 22: 12
  - Miscellaneous typescript draft of an article, 1956
    Box/Folder 22: 13
  - Miscellaneous typescript speech outlines, 1957
    Box/Folder 22: 14
  - Miscellaneous correspondence and speech outline, 1958
    Box/Folder 22: 15
  - "China Travel-boy," typescript article, circa 1963
    Box/Folder 22: 16
  - Miscellaneous typescript speech outlines, 1964
    Box/Folder 22: 17
  - Miscellaneous typescript speech outline, 1966
    Box/Folder 22: 18
  - Miscellaneous handwritten notes, 1968
    Box/Folder 22: 19
  - The China That I Knew, 1973
    - Correspondence, notes, and chapter outlines (Reel 37)
      Box/Folder 22: 20
    - Typescript draft
      Box/Folder 22: 21
    - Printed copy (softbound)
      Box/Folder 22: 22
- BUREAU OF ENGINEERING, CITY OF SAN FRANCISCO, 1908-1917
  Civil service examinations, clippings, correspondence and survey maps arranged alphabetically by physical form.
  - General
    Box/Folder 23: 1
  - Civil service examination announcements and results
    Box/Folder 23: 2
  - Clippings, Hetch Hetchy
    Box/Folder 23: 3
  - Correspondence, 1909-1917
    - General, 1909-1915
      Box/Folder 23: 4
    - Bartell, M. J., 1913
      Box/Folder 23: 5
    - Cheminant, L. B., 1914-1915
      Box/Folder 23: 6
    - Clapp, W. B., 1910-1911
      Box/Folder 23: 7
    - Freeman, John, 1911-1912
      Box/Folder 23: 8
    - Jones, D. A., 1909-1913
      Box/Folder 23: 9
    - Jones, D. A., 1914-1915 (Reel 38)
      Box/Folder 23: 10
    - Long, Percy V., 1914-1915
      Box/Folder 23: 11
    - McGlashan, H. D., 1911-1915
      Box/Folder 23: 12
    - Manson, Marsden, 1909-1912
      Box/Folder 24: 1
    - O'Shaughnessy, M. M., 1912-1915
      Box/Folder 24: 2
    - Parker, Carleton H., 1914
      Box/Folder 24: 3
    - Rankin, C. R., 1914-1915
      Box/Folder 24: 4
    - Ross, Louis, 1915
      Box/Folder 24: 5
  - Invoices, time sheets, and lists of supplies, 1912-1916
    Box/Folder 24: 6
  - Invoices, time sheets, and lists of supplies, 1912-1916 (Reel 39)
    Box/Folder 24: 7
  - Survey maps and charts
    Box/Folder 24: 8
- GRAND CANAL IMPROVEMENT BOARD, 1918-1936
  Charts, correspondence and reports arranged alphabetically by physical form.
  - General, 1918-1921
    Box/Folder 25: 1
  - Appointment of Todd, 1921
    Box/Folder 25: 2
  - Charts and drawings
    Box/Folder 25: 3
  - Correspondence, 1919-1922
    - General, 1919-1920
      Box/Folder 25: 4
    - Chiang, S. Y., 1920
      Box/Folder 25: 5
    - Fong, C. Y., 1919-1920
      Box/Folder 25: 6
    - Freeman, John R., 1919-1921
      Box/Folder 25: 7. See also SUBJECT FILE, Yellow River bridge contract bids.
    - Hsiao, C. L., 1920
      Box/Folder 25: 8
    - Leitzel, Henry S., 1920-1921
      Box/Folder 25: 9
    - Ling, Homer C., 1920
      Box/Folder 25: 10
    - Ripley, Joseph, 1919
      Box/Folder 25: 11
    - Wiggin, Thomas H., 1920-1936
      Box/Folder 25: 12
    - Yang, P. M., 1920-1922
      Box/Folder 25: 13
    - Young, S. S., 1920
      Box/Folder 25: 14
    - Yuan, C. M., 1920-1921
      Box/Folder 25: 15
  - Reports
    - Evaporation, 1920
      Box/Folder 25: 16
    - Hydrographic records, 1920-1921
      Box/Folder 25: 17
    - Rainfall data, 1919
      Box/Folder 25: 18
    - Ssu Ho Reservoir, 1919-1920 (Reel 40)
      Box/Folder 25: 19
    - Surveys (I), 1920-1921
      Box/Folder 25: 20
    - Surveys, Book II, 1919-1920
      Box/Folder 26: 1
    - Tawenkou Reservoir, 1920
      Box/Folder 26: 2
    - Wen Ho Reservoir, 1919-1920
      Box/Folder 26: 3
- AMERICAN NATIONAL RED CROSS and ASIA DEVELOPMENT COMPANY, 1921-1937
  Todd's work in these years was under the aegis of both organizations and sometimes overlapped. Correspondence, financial records, maps, personnel lists and reports arranged alphabetically by physical form.
  - General
    - Appointment and discharge of Todd, 1921-1923
      Box/Folder 26: 4
    - Contracts, 1922
      Box/Folder 26: 5
  - Correspondence
    - General, 1921
      Box/Folder 26: 6
    - General, 1922-1923
      Box/Folder 26: 7
    - Baker, John E., 1921-1923
      Box/Folder 26: 8
    - Hildabrand, Carl, 1922-1937
      Box/Folder 26: 9
    - Tucker, F. F., 1921-1923
      Box/Folder 26: 10
    - Whitham, Paul P., 1921-1924 (Reel 41)
      Box/Folder 26: 11
  - Financial records
    Box/Folder 26: 12
  - Invitations
    Box/Folder 26: 13
  - Legal documents: Todd vs Asia Development Company
    - General
      Box/Folder 26: 14
    - Rodger and Husar Law Office
      Box/Folder 26: 15
  - Maps
    Box/Folder 27: 1
  - Memoranda
    Box/Folder 27: 2
  - Newsletter, Monthly
    Box/Folder 27: 3
  - Personnel lists
    Box/Folder 27: 4
  - Photographs of work in progress with dates and captions (Reels 41-42)
    Box/Folder 27: 5-10
  - Relief committee reports
    - General (Reel 42)
      Box/Folder 28: 1-2
    - Hai Ho Conservancy Commission (Reel 43)
      Box/Folder 28: 3
    - Huai Valley Conservancy Board
      Box/Folder 28: 4
    - Hunan Chinese Foreign Famine Relief Committee
      Box/Folder 28: 5
    - Shantung International Relief Committee
      Box/Folder 28: 6
- CHINA INTERNATIONAL FAMINE RELIEF COMMISSION, 1923-1960
  Agreements, clippings, correspondence, maps, publications and reports arranged alphabetically by physical form.
  - General
    Box/Folder 28: 7
  - Agreements, contracts, and proposals, 1921-1928
    Box/Folder 29: 1
  - Clippings (Reel 44)
    Box/Folder 29: 2-4
  - Correspondence
    - General
      - Undated
        Box/Folder 29: 5
      - 1923
        Box/Folder 29: 6
      - 1924
        Box/Folder 29: 7
      - 1925
        Box/Folder 29: 8
      - 1926
        Box/Folder 29: 9
      - 1927
        Box/Folder 29: 10
      - 1928
        - General
          Box/Folder 29: 11
        - Good Roads Movement (Reel 45)
          Box/Folder 29: 12
      - 1929
        Box/Folder 29: 13
      - 1930
        Box/Folder 30: 1
      - 1930-1932 (Todd's salary)
        Box/Folder 30: 2
      - 1931
        Box/Folder 30: 3
      - 1932
        Box/Folder 30: 4
      - 1933
        Box/Folder 30: 5
      - 1934
        Box/Folder 30: 6
      - 1935
        Box/Folder 30: 7
      - 1936
        - General (Reel 46)
          Box/Folder 30: 8
        - Yellow River dike closure
          Box/Folder 30: 9
      - 1937
        Box/Folder 30: 10
      - 1938
        Box/Folder 30: 11
    - Baker, John Earl, 1927-1949
      Box/Folder 31: 1
    - Brown, David A., 1933-1937
      Box/Folder 31: 2
    - Chang, C. C., 1931-1946
      Box/Folder 31: 3. See also Saratsi irrigation project.
    - Chuan, S. Henry, 1932-1933
      Box/Folder 31: 4
    - Crane, Charles R., 1934-1939
      Box/Folder 31: 5
    - Eliassen, Sigurd
      - 1923-1935 (Reel 47)
        Box/Folder 31: 6
      - 1933, capture and release by bandits
        Box/Folder 31: 7
      - 1936
        Box/Folder 31: 8
      - 1937-1938
        Box/Folder 31: 9
      - 1939-1960
        Box/Folder 31: 10
    - Freeman, John R.
      - 1920-1922
        Box/Folder 32: 1
      - 1923-1931 (Reel 48)
        Box/Folder 32: 2
      - 1932-1933
        Box/Folder 32: 3
    - Gunn, Selskar, 1934-1937
      Box/Folder 32: 4
    - Hendry, John L., Jr., 1923-1927
      Box/Folder 32: 5
    - Hsu, Shu-hsi, 1936-1938
      Box/Folder 32: 6
    - Kelly, William
      - 1934-1935
        Box/Folder 32: 7
      - 1936-1937
        Box/Folder 32: 8
      - 1938-1956
        Box/Folder 32: 9
    - Kung, H. Y., 1936-1937
      Box/Folder 32: 10
    - Liang, M. T., 1926-1938 (Reel 49)
      Box/Folder 32: 11
    - Liu, John, 1936-1937
      Box/Folder 33: 1
    - Lively, D. O.
      - 1930-1932
        Box/Folder 33: 2
      - 1933
        Box/Folder 33: 3
    - Mallory, Walter H., 1923-1945
      Box/Folder 33: 4
    - Soong, T. V., 1927-1933
      Box/Folder 33: 5
    - Tan, Chen, 1921-1946
      Box/Folder 33: 6
    - Thomson, Andrew, 1937
      Box/Folder 33: 7
    - Tornvall, Gustaf, Case of, 1932-1933
      Box/Folder 33: 8
    - Vanderburgh, Richard M., 1925-1936 (Reel 50)
      Box/Folder 33: 9
    - Waddell, J. A. L.
      - 1923-1933
        Box/Folder 33: 10
      - 1934-1938
        Box/Folder 33: 11
    - Wirt, Lincoln, 1935-1937
      Box/Folder 33: 12
  - Financial records
    - Budgets, 1923-1935
      - General
        Box/Folder 33: 13
      - Famine Fund Drive, 1928
        Box/Folder 33: 14
    - Expense accounts (Todd's), 1922-1927
      Box/Folder 33: 15
  - Maps, charts, and diagrams
    Box/Folder 33: 16
  - Memoranda
    Box/Folder 34: 1
  - Photographs of work in progress with date and captions including work at the Hopei-Shantung border, Linpuchi and Shensi, 1936
    Box/Folder 34: 2-3
  - Printed material
    - Annual reports, 1924-1930 (Reels 50-51)
      Box/Folder 34: 4-5
    - Annual reports, 1931-1936 (Reel 51)
      Box/Folder 35: 1
    - C.I.F.R.C. News Bulletin, 1936 April 1 (Reel 52)
      Box/Folder 35: 2
    - Engineering Accomplishments, 1921-1933
      Box/Folder 35: 3
    - Famine Commission Bulletin
      - 1923-1931
        Box/Folder 35: 4
      - 1932-1936
        Box/Folder 35: 5
    - The Huang Ho
      Box/Folder 35: 6
    - Hydrology of the Yellow River
      Box/Folder 35: 7
    - The Present Condition and a Discussion of the Fundamental Conservancy Measures for the Yellow River
      Box/Folder 35: 8
    - The Yellow River Crevasse Closure Work at Tung Chuang (Reel 53)
      Box/Folder 36: 1
  - Reports
    - Cut-off channel for Yellow River control work, typescripts
      Box/Folder 36: 2
    - Dike breaks at Li Chin and Linpuchi, typescripts
      Box/Folder 36: 3
    - Famine prevention projects, typescripts
      Box/Folder 36: 4
    - Various issues of Series A and B on aspects of famine relief
      Box/Folder 36: 5
  - Special engineering problems, proposals, surveys, and studies
    - Fen Ho Dam, 1932-1934
      Box/Folder 36: 6
    - Hupeh dikes, 1924-1927 (Reel 54)
      Box/Folder 36: 7
    - Kweichow road work, 1927-1928
      Box/Folder 37: 1
    - Saratsi irrigation project, 1928-1935
      - Correspondence, 1927-1936
        Box/Folder 37: 2
      - Description of project
        Box/Folder 37: 3
      - Eliassen's charts and surveys
        Box/Folder 37: 4
      - League of Nations report
        Box/Folder 37: 5
      - Maps and charts
        Box/Folder 37: 6
      - Memoranda, notes, clippings (Reel 55)
        Box/Folder 37: 7
      - Reports (include photographs)
        Box/Folder 37: 8
    - Tenghow Weir
      Box/Folder 37: 9
  - Subject file
    - American Committee for the Engineering Foundation correspondence
      Box/Folder 37: 10
    - Golden Rule Foundation campaign
      Box/Folder 37: 11
  - Travel schedules
    Box/Folder 37: 12
- UNITED STATES. DEPARTMENT OF THE INTERIOR. BUREAU OF RECLAMATION, 1940-1942
  Personnel memoranda and reports arranged alphabetically by physical form.
  - General
    Box/Folder 38: 1
  - Personnel memoranda regarding Todd's service rating and salary
    Box/Folder 38: 2
  - Report on aggradation and silt control of the Middle Rio Grande Valley
    Box/Folder 38: 3
- UNITED STATES. ARMY ENGINEERS, 1936-1945
  Charts, correspondence, memoranda and reports arranged alphabetically by physical form.
  - General
    Box/Folder 38: 4
  - Charts and diagrams
    Box/Folder 38: 5
  - Correspondence
    - General, 1943-1945
      Box/Folder 38: 6
    - Lowdermilk, Walter C., 1945
      Box/Folder 38: 7
    - Memoranda, 1936-1945
      Box/Folder 38: 8
    - Office circulars, 1944-1945 (Reel 56)
      Box/Folder 38: 9
    - Todd's personnel records, 1943-1945
      Box/Folder 38: 10
  - Reports
    - East Twin Creek Flood Control Channel, 1943
      Box/Folder 38: 11
    - Santa Inez River, 1944
      Box/Folder 38: 12
    - Tucson, Arizona, Development of, 1944
      Box/Folder 38: 13
    - Whitewater River Flood Control Channel, 1944
      Box/Folder 38: 14
- UNITED NATIONS RELIEF AND REHABILITATION ADMINISTRATION, 1943-1970
  Correspondence, charts, maps, memoranda, personnel lists, reports arranged by physical form.
  - General
    - General, 1946-1947
      Box/Folder 39: 1. Includes use photocopy of UNRRA guest book. Original withdrawn from use.
    - Equipment lists and requisitions
      Box/Folder 39: 2
    - Personal papers and mementoes
      Box/Folder 39: 3
    - Statement of criticism of Todd
      Box/Folder 39: 4
  - Clippings (Reel 57)
    Box/Folder 39: 5-6
  - Correspondence
    - General
      - 1943-1947
        - General
          Box/Folder 39: 7
        - Reference letters and job offer to Todd
          Box/Folder 39: 8
      - Personal to and from Todd, 1945-1947
        Box/Folder 39: 9
      - Includes a letter from Chou En-Lai to Todd, 1946 May 21 (Reel 58)
        Box/Folder 40: 1
      - 1947
        - General
          Box/Folder 40: 2
        - Saratsi Irrigation Project
          Box/Folder 40: 3
    - Chang, C. C., 1946-1947
      - General
        Box/Folder 40: 4
      - Death of C. C. Chang, 1947 April-May
        Box/Folder 40: 5
    - Eliassen, Sigurd, 1945-1947
      Box/Folder 40: 6
    - Powell, Helen, 1946-1947
      Box/Folder 40: 7
  - Inventories of supplies
    Box/Folder 40: 8
  - Maps and charts
    Box/Folder 40: 9
  - Memoranda (Reel 59)
    Box/Folder 40: 10
  - Personnel lists and forms
    Box/Folder 40: 11
  - Photographs of work in progress with dates and captions
    Box/Folder 40: 12
  - Photographs of work in progress with dates and captions
    Box/Folder 41: 1
  - Reports
    - General
      - First Session of the Council of the United Nations Relief and Rehabilitation Administration, Selected Documents, printed copy, 1943
        Box/Folder 41: 2
      - Miscellaneous weekly reports
        Box/Folder 41: 3
      - Report of the Director General to the Council, printed copy, 1947 March
        Box/Folder 41: 4
    - China's Yellow River, monograph
      Box/Folder 41: 5. Attached exhibits include reports to General S. Y. Chao, Chairman, Yellow River commission, Honan; General George C. Marshall, Cease-fire Committee, Nanking; General Chou En-lai, Communist delegation.
    - History of the Yellow River Project by O. J. Todd, 1947 March
      Box/Folder 41: 6
    - Rainfall data (Reel 60)
      Box/Folder 41: 7
    - UNRRA in China, 1945-1947
      Box/Folder 41: 8
    - UNRRA Relief for the Chinese People, A Report by CLARA (China Liberated Areas Relief Association), 1947
      Box/Folder 41: 9
    - Water and Land Problems in China by C. P. Christopoulos, 1947
      Box/Folder 41: 10
    - Yellow River data (Reel 61)
      Box/Folder 42: 1
    - Yellow River Supply Analysis (final audit), 1947
      Box/Folder 42: 2
  - Subject file, 1945-1970
    - Dike repair at Shantung, memoranda
      Box/Folder 42: 3
    - Hunger Fighters in China, 1947-1970
      A newsletter written at irregular intervals by and for the members and former members of UNRRA's Agricultural Rehabilitation Division of the China Office.
      - Correspondence
        Box/Folder 42: 4
      - Issues
        - 1947
          Box/Folder 42: 5
        - 1948-1951
          Box/Folder 42: 6
        - 1952-1953
          Box/Folder 42: 7
        - 1954-1955 (Reel 62)
          Box/Folder 43: 1
        - 1956-1959
          Box/Folder 43: 2
        - 1960-1963
          Box/Folder 43: 3
        - 1964 (Reel 63)
          Box/Folder 43: 4
        - 1964-1966
          Box/Folder 44: 1
        - Draft of an issue edited by Todd, 1967
          Box/Folder 44: 2
        - 1967-1970
          Box/Folder 44: 3
  - Travel and expense accounts (Reel 64)
    Box/Folder 44: 4
- JOINT COMMISSION ON RURAL RECONSTRUCTION, 1949-1951
  Correspondence, maps, memoranda, personnel records, reports arranged alphabetically by physical form.
  - General
    Box/Folder 44: 5-6
  - Clippings
    - General
      Box/Folder 44: 7
    - Yung Ting Ho
      Box/Folder 44: 8
  - Correspondence
    - General
      - 1949
        Box/Folder 45: 1
      - 1950
        Box/Folder 45: 2
      - 1951 (Reel 65)
        Box/Folder 45: 3
    - Baker, John Earl, 1949-1950
      Box/Folder 45: 4
    - Barrett, David D., 1950
      Box/Folder 45: 5
    - Powell, Helen, 1949-1951
      Box/Folder 45: 6
  - Financial records
    Box/Folder 45: 7
  - Maps, charts, and diagrams
    - General
      Box/Folder 45: 8
    - Irrigation upkeep
      Box/Folder 45: 9
  - Memoranda
    - 1949
      Box/Folder 45: 10
    - 1950
      - General
        Box/Folder 45: 11
      - Air raid shelters and drills
        Box/Folder 45: 12
    - 1951
      Box/Folder 45: 13
  - Miscellaneous
    Box/Folder 45: 14
  - Personnel records
    - General
      Box/Folder 45: 15
    - Appointment and resignation of Todd
      Box/Folder 45: 16
  - Press releases
    Box/Folder 46: 1
  - Printed matter
    Box/Folder 46: 2
  - Reports
    - General
      Box/Folder 46: 3
    - Irrigation Engineering Division
      - General
        Box/Folder 46: 4
      - History of Engineering Program, JCRR (Reel 66)
        Box/Folder 46: 5
      - Investigations and analyses
        Box/Folder 46: 6
      - Programs and proposals
        Box/Folder 46: 7
      - Waterworks
        Box/Folder 46: 8
      - Weekly Activity Reports
        Box/Folder 46: 9
    - Land Division
      Box/Folder 46: 10
  - Subject file
    - Economic Cooperation Administration, Press translation summary and memoranda
      Box/Folder 47: 1
    - Friends of China Club bulletins
      Box/Folder 47: 2
    - Lapham Mission, Applications to the
      Box/Folder 47: 3
    - Szechuan Project, correspondence and memoranda
      - Undated - 1949 July
        Box/Folder 47: 4
      - 1949 August (Reel 67)
        Box/Folder 47: 5
      - 1949 September
        Box/Folder 47: 6
      - 1949 October
        Box/Folder 47: 7
      - 1949 November
        Box/Folder 47: 8
  - Travel vouchers
    Box/Folder 47: 9
- SUBJECT FILE, 1906-1973
  Correspondence, printed material, publications arranged alphabetically by subject.
  - General
    Box/Folder 48: 1-2
  - China
    - Clippings
      Box/Folder 48: 3
    - Description and travel pamphlets (Reel 68)
      Box/Folder 48: 4-6
    - Description and travel pamphlets (Reels 69-69A)
      Box/Folder 49: 1-2
  - China issues, 1929-1936 (Reel 70)
    Box/Folder 49: 3
  - Chinese News Service, various issues, 1961-1962
    Box/Folder 50: 1-2
  - Commission for the Improvement of the River System of Chihli, Public Statement, Nos. 1-5
    Box/Folder 50: 3
    - Final Report and Grand Scheme, 1918-1925
      Box/Folder 50: 4
    - General Report(s), 1921, 1923, 1924 (Reel 71)
      Box/Folder 50: 5
    - Instructions for Staff and Employees, 1920
      Box/Folder 50: 6
    - Report on the Partial Conversion of Pei Ho, 1921
      Box/Folder 50: 7
  - Democracy, various issues and correspondence, 1937
    Box/Folder 50: 8
  - Geneal Rpeort (sic) of the Directorate-General for the Repairing of the Yung Ting Ho Dyke Breaches of, 1924
    Box/Folder 50: 9
  - Japan
    Box/Folder 51: 1
  - Letter from China by Anna Louise Strong, four issues, 1963-1964 (Reel 72)
    Box/Folder 51: 2
  - News Letter, The United Nations Association of the Republic of China, various issues, 1961-1963
    Box/Folder 51: 3
  - Notes on the Hwangho, or Yellow River; Including Extracts from a Report on the Condition of the South Bank Immediately Below Lo-K'ou, 1906
    Box/Folder 51: 4
  - "The Operation of the Hai Ho Palliative Scheme in the Summer (of) 1933" by C. Y. Kao
    Box/Folder 51: 5
  - Peitaiho (summer residence), 1938-1946
    Box/Folder 51: 6
  - River Conservancy Commission for Kwangtung Province, National Government, Publication No. 22
    Box/Folder 51: 7
  - The Week in China, various issues, 1928-1931
    Box/Folder 51: 8
  - William Winter Comments, various issues, 1965-1967
    Box/Folder 51: 9
  - World Engineering Congress, Tokyo, 1929 (Reel 73)
    Box/Folder 51: 10
    Includes correspondence, member lists, and schedules.
  - Yellow River bridge construction proposals, 1921
    Box/Folder 52: 1
  - "Yellow River Commission Proposal for an Aerial Inspection and Surveying Service with Landing Fields,", 1936 September
    Box/Folder 52: 2
  - The Yellow River Commission Survey Department, Field Instructions for Survey Work, 1934
    Box/Folder 52: 3
- OVERSIZE MATERIALS, 1918-1947 (Reels 74-76)
  Boxes 53-56. Engineering drawings, maps, diagrams, scrapbooks of clippings about the Yellow River system and Taiwan's rivers and irrigation system.
- MEMORABILIA, 1901-1951
  - School certificates, World War I items including a miniature Croix de Guerre, flags, scrolls, banners, chopsticks, a mounted tintype and UNRRA shoulder patches, a mounted silver plaque from the provincial government of Shensi, (boxed), 1932 June 20 (Reel 77, Box 58)
    Material from Box 57 on microfilm reel 77. Box 58 not filmed.
  - Twenty Chinese bronze mirrors from various dynasties located in the memorabilia cabinet in the Lou Henry Hoover Building lobby (Reading room Workstation)
- AUDIOVISUAL FILE, 1908-1964
  Circa 7,000 photographs, slides, post cards and moving pictures relating to Todd and family members, China, China leaders, and all phases of his work on the water systems at Hetch Hetchy, China's Yellow River and in Taiwan.
  - Postcards (Reel 78, Box 60)
    Box 59 on microfilm reel 78. Box 60 not filmed. Contains 48 booklets of detachable post cards; 647 individual cards and 3 packets of cards and one duplicate, depicting scenes, cities, buildings and artwork in Belgium, China, France, Hong Kong, Italy, Taiwan, the United Kingdom and the United States.
  - Slides
    - One stereoscope and 100 slides of a set titled "Editions Stereoscopeques de Guerre" depicting war damage, 1917-1918 (Box 61)
    - 84 glass slides depicting Yellow River projects in China (Box 62)